INTERNATIONAL BROTHERHOOD OF PAINTERS AND ALLIED TRADES OF THE UNITED STATES AND CANADA, LOCAL 201 RECORDS (APAP052) 1900-1982
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
International Brotherhood of Painters and Allied Trades of the United States and Canada, Local 201 Records1900-1982
nam_apap052
The collection documents the history of the unions that formed Painters and Allied Trades Local 201, including Local 12 of Troy, Local 62 of Schenectady, and Local 201 of Albany.
International Brotherhood of Painters and Allied Trades. Local 201 (Albany Metropolitan Area (N.Y.)
2.0
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
Administrative History
Painters and Allied Trades Local 201 represent painters in Albany, Schenectady, and Rensselaer counties of New York. The local was formed in 1982 from a merger of Local 12 of Troy, Local 62 of Schenectady, and Local 201 of Albany.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains minutes of Local 62 (1936-1944, 1965-1982), and Local 201 (1962-1981), membership ledgers of Local 12 (1922-1951, and contracts of Local 201. Local 201's minutes from 1978-1981 are closed until further notice.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection has no series, arranged chronologically by local and then chronologically by records.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by Local 201 of the International Brotherhood of Painters and Allied Trade. 1990 July
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Material Access Restrictions
Minutes, 1978-1981
Closed.
Subject and Genre Headings
Schenectady, New York; Rensselaer County, New York; Labor; Albany, New York; International Brotherhood of Painters and Allied Trades. Local 201 (Albany Metropolitan Area (N.Y.)); International Brotherhood of Painters and Allied Trades. Local 62 (Schenectady, N.Y.); International Brotherhood of Painters and Allied Trades. Local 12 (Troy, N.Y.); House painters -- Labor unions -- New York (State) --Albany Metropolitan Area; Paperhangers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) --Albany Metropolitan Area; Painters, Industrial -- Labor unions -- New York (State); Construction workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State); Minutes; Contracts; Registers (lists)
Container List
- Local 12 Membership Ledgers, 1922-1923 (Box 1)
- Local 12 Membership Ledgers, 1924-1925 (Box 1)
- Local 12 Membership Ledgers, 1926-1927 (Box 1)
- Local 12 Membership Ledgers, 1928-1929 (Box 1)
- Local 12 Membership Ledgers, 1930-1931 (Box 1)
- Local 12 Membership Ledgers, 1932-1933 (Box 1)
- Local 12 Membership Ledgers, 1934-1936 (Box 1)
- Local 12 Membership Ledgers, 1937-1938 (Box 1)
- Local 12 Membership Ledgers, 1939-1942 (Box 1)
- Local 12 Membership Ledgers, 1943-1946 (Box 2)
- Local 12 Membership Ledgers, 1947-1950 (Box 2)
- Local 12 Membership Ledgers, 1951-1953 (Box 2)
- Local 62 Minutes, 1936-1944 (Box 3)
- Local 62 Minutes, 1965-1979 (Box 3)
- Local 62 Minutes, 1979-1982 (Box 3)
- Local 201 Contracts, 1965; 1970; 1973; 1976; 1982 (Box 4)
- Local 201 Membership Book, Sample, 1900 (Box 4)
- Local 201 Minutes, 1964-1981 (Box 4)